brighamandwomens.org 2018-03-28

# Website Consent & Privacy Policy - Brigham and Women's Hospital

At Brigham and Women's Hospital, we are committed to using all reasonable efforts to protect the privacy and security of the users of our website. We understand that health is a very personal, private subject. This Website Consent and Privacy Policy will inform you about the information we collect, how it is used, and what choices are available to you. Please read this policy carefully. Whenever a necessary change is made to our policy, we will update the information on this page so please check back regularly.

  1. What does it mean for you to give consent?
  2. What circumstances require additional information from you?
  3. Does Brigham and Women's Hospital use "cookies" or IP addresses to collect user information?
  4. Are there advertisements on Brigham and Women's Hospital website?
  5. How does Brigham and Women's Hospital handle privacy internally?
  6. Which web pages and websites does this policy apply to?
  7. What are unique policies for website visitors under the age of 13, those who are California residents, and international users?
  8. How can claims of copyright infringement be reported?

**1\. What does it mean for you to give consent?**   
By using the Brigham and Women's web site, you agree to accept this Privacy Policy and its terms. We may occasionally need to make changes to our Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our site and address new issues.

By providing us with an e-mail address, you agree that we may use your e-mail address to communicate with you about our services and select messages from our partners or affiliates. While you cannot opt-out of receiving notifications and other communications regarding your account or your transactions, you can opt-out of receiving promotional and other marketing e-mails from us by using the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email communication.

Back to Top

**2\. What circumstances require additional information from you?**  
You may use most of [https://www.brighamandwomens.org](https://www.brighamandwomens.org/) and [https://brighamhealthhub.org](https://brighamhealthhub.org/) without providing any personal information. When you reply to any of our communications with a request, we may need to collect additional personal information. For example, you may be asked to provide personal information, such as demographic information, if you choose to complete any of the online forms used for class registration, special events and promotions, appointment requests, and to provide feedback. Additional questions may be included to help us improve the services we offer. It is important to remember that only designated staff within Partners HealthCare will have access on a need to know basis to the information you provide.

Please do not provide personal information via e-mail to the hospital unless it is through a secure channel (these will be marked, as secure online forms, for example). Remember that e-mail messages, unless encrypted while in transit, can be viewed by other Internet users. If you have individualized information to communicate, please use the appropriate secure online form or contact the necessary party using traditional means such as phone or mail.

If you wish to subscribe to our Health E-Newsletter, we collect and store first and last names and e-mail address. This information is used for distribution purposes. If you would like to unsubscribe from our e-mail newsletters, please use the link at the bottom of every e-mail communication or you can e-mail your request to [BWHweb@partners.org](mailto:BWHweb@partners.org).

As explained in the section below, we also collect and log the IP address (and identification number associated with your computer) when you visit the hospital’s web site.

Brigham and Women's currently uses all reasonable efforts to protect against disclosure of personal information you provide on our website, except if we need to process credit card information you have given us or as required by law. We have no current plans to make other disclosures of such information. If this changes, we will post a revised on-line privacy policy.

Brigham and Women's Hospital may occasionally provide statistics to third parties related to the number of visitors who use the site. These statistics do not provide personally identifiable information.

Back to Top

**3\. Does Brigham and Women's Hospital use "cookies" or IP Addresses to collect user information?**  
Cookies are small pieces of information that some websites store on your computer’s hard drive when you visit them. Like many other websites, brighamandwomens.org uses aggregate data compiled by cookies to provide us with information about traffic to our site. Collecting this information does not allow us to personally identify you. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can set your browser to refuse them or to alert you when they are being sent. You may modify your web browsers to reject cookies from our site if you wish. You can access the information on the Brigham and Women's Hospital web site without having cookies enabled in your browser.

We collect and log the IP address (an identification number associated with your computer) of all visitors to brighamandwomens.org. This allows us to administer our system to gather aggregate information about how our site is being used. To maintain your privacy, we do not associate IP addresses with records containing personal health information.

We may use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., and other online analytics services on our sites. These analytic services help us analyze how users interact with and use the web site, compile reports on the web site activity, and provide other services related to web site activity and usage. These technologies may use cookies and collect information such as your IP address, time of visit, whether you are a return visitor, any referring website, and other information. We do not use Google Analytics to gather information that personally identifies you. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser.

Back to Top

**4. Are there advertisements on Brigham and Women's Hospital web site?**  
At present, Brigham and Women's Hospital does not accept advertisements on its website.

Back to Top

**5\. How does Brigham and Women's Hospital handle privacy internally?**  
Brigham and Women's Hospital is committed to protecting the privacy of the personal information you provide to us via this website so that we can make sure it remains as secure as possible. Accordingly, we use all reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized access by a secure firewall and use a security infrastructure that protects the integrity and privacy of such personal information. As an additional security measure, your personal information is also encrypted during transmission by Secure Socket Layer 128-bit encryption software. Encryption is a common method used to transmit sensitive data across the Internet. Encryption temporarily makes the text unreadable during the time it is being transmitted over the Internet.

Back to Top

**6. Which web pages and websites does this policy apply to?**  
This online Privacy Policy applies only to the Brigham and Women's Hospital [https://www.brighamandwomens.org](https://www.brighamandwomens.org/) and the Brigham Health Hub [https://brighamhealthhub.org](https://brighamhealthhub.org/) websites. The Brigham and Women's Hospital site contains links to other sites, within and outside of Partners HealthCare. Please be aware that this online policy does not apply to those sites. We encourage you to read the Privacy Policy on any other sites before providing them with personal information.

Certain interactive patient transactions may be linked to this site as a convenience for you. If you choose to utilize a specific patient application, please be sure to read the privacy policy associated with that particular transaction. [Partners Patient Gateway](https://www.patientgateway.org/), which offers patients secure electronic messaging to participating Brigham and Women's Hospital practices, is an example of such a patient application.

Please note that the Partners Privacy Notice more generally explains the Hospital’s and Partners’ commitment to protect the privacy of personal health information.

Back to Top

**7. What are unique policies for website visitors under the age of 13, those who are California residents, and international users?**  
Our website is intended only for users who are 13 years of age and older. Accordingly, we will not knowingly collect or use any personal information from children that we know to be under the age of 13. If we become aware of personal information in our database that was collected from a child under 13, we will delete such information.

If you are a California resident, California law permits you to request certain information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by us and our related companies to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send your request by e-mail to [BWHweb@partners.org](mailto:BWHweb@partners.org).

When our website is used outside of the United States, the user understands and provides consent to the transfer of personal information to, and the collection, processing, and storage of personal information in the United States and elsewhere. The laws in the U.S. and these countries regarding personal information may be different than the laws of your state or country.

Back to Top

**8\. How can claims of copyright infringement be reported?**  
In accordance with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA), 17 U.S.C. § 512 (the “DCMA”) The Brigham and Women's Hospitals. INC. (“Brigham and Women's Hospital”) is registered as a Service Provider with the United States Copyright Office. Notifications of copyright infringement claims occurring on the Brigham and Women's Hospital network should be reported to our designated agent, as follows:

**Partners Healthcare System, Inc.**  
One Constitution Center, 1st floor   
Charlestown, MA 02129

**E-mail:**[dmca-agent@partners.org](mailto:dmca-agent@partners.org)

**Any such notice must be in writing, and must include the following information as required by the DMCA:**

  * A physical or electronic signature of the copyright owner or the person authorized to act on its behalf
  * A description of the copyrighted work claimed to have been infringed;
  * A description of the infringing material and information reasonably sufficient to permit Brigham and Women's Hospital to locate the material;
  * Your contact information, including your address, telephone number, and e-mail;
  * A statement by you that you have a good faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; and
  * A statement that the information in the notification is accurate, and, under the pains and penalties of perjury, that you are authorized to act on behalf of the copyright owner.

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at https://www.brighamandwomens.org/forms/contact-bwh-important-phone-numbers.

Back to Top
